so I thought um to talk about um you
know how the sutas often say
um established in
virtue so it's it's even like kind of
almost used synonymously with getting
the right view you'll be like that's
what that monk wanted to go in
solitude and the Buddha and then well
the Buddha told him not to he ignored
him went there had a hard time couldn't
control his mind came came back and said
that to the Buddha and the Buddha said
well indeed for as long as one is not
established in
virtue uh or has Jan properly like the
mind of Jan developed or um has a right
view it's to be expected then the the
thoughts of sensuality would overwhelm
him in solitude and so
on um
so I guess the question
is
how one gets established in
virtue is it enough to just keep the
precepts or would just keeping the
precepts automatically or eventually
result in establishment in
virtue which is as I said virtually like
like getting the right
View you're saying if you just keep I
don't kill anyone I don't steal and
that's yeah just keeping the precepts
somebody's just keeping the
precepts does that mean they're
established in virtue or do you need to
do something
more reflect on
why uh the value of of the precepts of
virtue and the danger of
of not keeping the precept well I'm sure
people who just keep the precepts do
that it's not that they don't think
about it so is that would that be enough
to be EST is that is that enough to
become
s with with the
right instruction in again
um they hear the right instruction on
account of which they keep the precepts
and reflect upon their intention
so is that enough for S is that enough
to be close to the mind of Jan and ready
for the Solitude and overcome everything
else yeah like you have what is
something else
missing well you have to understand what
virtue is what non virtue is meaning you
have to you can say I I won't kill
anyone but you know why would I kill
anyone what what are the qualities would
make me kill anymore and
then remove those qualities which could
be you know for example
anger anger towards resistance towards
painful feeling and if I remove that
that craving
then I cannot kill anyone I cannot break
any precepts
mhm and then by removing that craving
then I'm established in
virtue because I don't have a basis for
virtue
any what was
that yeah so it's not
about the rules of the precepts
specifically but
about um um
well understanding
why he why they are always wrong
basically and what would is there a
simpler way of answering this question
CU you know like we understand
understanding the value and why but say
somebody who's not as familiar with all
these kind of jargon so to speak is
there a way of development that they can
do that would result in establishment of
virtue so it's
it's the precepts that you start with
but what else is lacking in regard to
those precepts for somebody who is
keeping them but is not established in
virtue and they can be keeping them for
50 years but still not be established in
that
virtue so like we can even think in
terms of the the the faith type you know
the one that does not necessarily have a
vast amount of information on the
knowledge of the sutas but
has has his confidence
established in the right instruction
that leads from merely keeping the
precepts all the way to Aran it's the
it's that that same threat that he has
grasped and has enough confidence to do
it so what is that threat what is that
that he would need to do so keeping the
precepts is obviously not enough on its
own what else again within the same
framework what do they need to
do not act out of
craving but that's what I said you not
act yeah CU yeah the full understanding
of craving it sort of feeds not acting
out and not acting out but it takes time
to get there so not distracting yourself
but that's it in a way yeah that's
closer now to the to the to what I'm
what I'm aiming
at self-reflection in the sense that
again that can sure again the term
self-reflection can mean anything for
anybody really they can take that to
mean reevaluating the but just like on
the basis of precepts what do people not
do even when they keep the precepts
where do they what do they La where do
they stop
short thinking why they're doing
they might think about they doing it but
still won't do
it so let's start with this so what is
the what do the precepts apply to what
are they supposed to purify precepts the
intentions more coarsely than
that harming yourself and others bodily
Behavior bodily Behavior yeah okay so
you start with a bodily
behavior and again just we're keeping it
very simple I'm not asking for like
abstract complex answers just somebody
who heard the Buddha once and uhhuh I
can do that and did it and became an
arant without any other instruction so
they would start okay
presets are the kind of um a course
container well container for the course
bodily misbehavior so you contain
that and uh do they need to stay there
that container can that container be
taken
further so you have body what else do
you have speech and mind yeah so the
main reason then that somebody is not
established in the precepts is because
they have not applied them on these
three levels so in the same way you're
levels so in the same way you're
restraining your bodily
Behavior you need to restrain your
speech same way exactly same way
no no other information or reasoning
necessary and then in the same way you
restrain your body and your speech you
need to restrain your mental images
which ones you revolve around and you
realize oh yeah no most people don't do
that even people they as I say can keep
the precepts for hundreds of years you
realize are you never hear the part
about restraining your mind on that
right level like you might hear about
level like you might hear about
concentrate on this and when this is
present you do that but all of those are
actions and
reactions just in the same way you
abstain from intentionally giving into
certain bodily
behavior in the same way you abstain
from giving into certain verbal
Behavior it's exactly the
same thing that you're doing basically
that's something that people might not
see because they might say in theory
okay yes I need to be purified in my
mind as well but they might think think
that that is something different than
the bodily and verbal behavior and
that's what I mean that's why they would
remain keeping the precepts for decades
and not become established in
virtue because but it's in the same
sutas they talk about keeping the
precepts he carries on talking about how
to then keep the speech and keep the
mind so to speak so it's it's laid out
in the same manner in the same sutas in
the same way but it's somehow there is
that kind of okay no this applies up to
here and the rest of this okay speech
Yes people can see there is some input
of their own but when it comes to mind
oh that will somehow magically happen on
account of this practice or that
practice but you realize no no no you
are fully responsible when you have
images of sensuality as I said well you
know you can try to deny them and and
distract yourself from it and replace
that experience with another but there
is no there is no
restraint and there's certainly no
understanding of it
or you could if you if you have such
images or images of ill will that's
probably even more easier to relate for
people so if you're annoyed by somebody
by person specifically you're going to
have images of them of that experience
of of what you should have all of these
images that revolve around that
experience you're going to have your
mind have them and you are the one who
then chooses to as I said before rest on
those images and allow them to then
perpetuate themselves you don't have to
fight them you don't have to try and get
rid of them but you certainly need to
not give them your uh wrong attention in
that manner so don't allow your mind to
rest on them and don't lose the
reference point in regard to those
images and that's how you restrain your
mind so restraining the mind in regard
to the unsuitable images it's not on the
level of trying to get rid of the images
or not have them arise in the first
place it's on the level of learning how
to not give them the wrong attention not
have them at Center Stage yeah not have
them in the center basically that then
kind of makes the whole thing revolve
around it and that's again that is on
the basis of the intentional effort it's
not like CU again see even that is so
invisible to people that they would
think oh so I need to practice this
moment to moment concentration to catch
these little moments in between these
thoughts that's not where these things
are if you have been restraining your
body in other words restraining the
course Outlets toward cality Will
um and other UNH wholesome things
then on top of that you restrain your
speech and there are again many
instances in the sutas uh what type of
speech speech you should not be engaging
in and again that's on the basis of the
intentional effort you intentionally not
allow yourself to become established on
like in the experience of bad speech in
regard to this in regard to that in
regard to gossip malice careless chatter
all of that when you C no you don't do
it again I don't have to get rid of the
intention or having to feel guilty for
doing it no once you catch it on that
level that's when you stop when you
realize that it's it's on the basis of
your choice and then the same leads to
the choice on that mental in regard to
the mental
images when they present themselves you
realize you have a choice will I
continue to give them the center stage
and then divorce myself from the
experience of here and now and whatever
else was doing and let my mind kind of
run with it or will I say no I will not
allow that let them be there but I will
not allow my mind to focus on them
fully cuz that is a choice so what do
you do so obviously we've all heard that
suo it says you know he destroys those
thoughts he obliterates them yeah he he
smashes them out of existence yeah but
then he describes how yeah so how do you
smash them out of existence how do you
get rid of it how do you how do you
destroy those thoughts by not thinking
out of them yeah by by by practicing Y
in regard to them the suas very clearly
say that it's the properly attended
thoughts so see in order to attend
something properly or improperly it
needs to be there that's the point so
these thoughts are there so the question
is not not having those thoughts the
question is oh not attending to them
mistakenly or uh UNC concurrently Inc
concurrently I say but to attend to them
rightly so all you need to do in regard
to sweeping the leaves and having the
thoughts of ill will is not I focus hard
on the moments and sensations of leaves
so these thoughts don't bother me nor is
it I'll forget about sweeping the leaves
or I'll even stop sweeping the leaves
and I'll just resolve this in my mind
it's basically recognizing that both
they're there simultaneously
present so you have thought of ill will
images associated with with the person
that upset you and you do have
recognition of what you're doing here
and now through your other
senses establishing that balance between
the two is enough to not wrongly attend
to ill will it's enough to not wrongly
attend to sensuality it's enough to not
wrongly attend to any
hindrance and once that becomes more
palpable you realize oh yeah I
obliterate them by not giving by not
feeding them through wrong
acknowledgement and mistaken attention
so the recognition of this like
simultaneous two domains enduring you
sweeping the leaves talking here and
mind thinking certain thoughts at the
same time you're not denying it but
you're certainly not uh forgetting which
you where you are on account of
it and I mean a good point as well is
that
it is important to realize that you can
if you are like a afraid of having such
thoughts or even you know seeing
yourself having such thoughts you don't
want to kind of admit them to yourself
or something uh you don't want to be
having those thoughts that in in itself
will make it hard to actually correctly
attend them because you will be like
trying to by trying to ignore them
you're actually already way of WR way of
attending them you're giving them that
wrong attention and actually that's
allowing them to proliferate there in
the background just ignoring that and
that's really the root of all un
wholesome so the presence of those
images in regard to sensuality or images
in regard to a will or in regard to
worry that's not the root of unh
wholesome that's not the root of
suffering that's in in those numerous
sues inut where said there is not a
single thing such
Asar the incur intention that makes UNH
wholesome things increase wholesome
decrease and honor is an unh wholesome
to
arise and consequently there's not a
single thing that makes UNH wholesome
things decrease and wholesome increase
such as y so that is the root of it and
um and that's exactly how one becomes
established in virtue You Realize by
practicing the
same restraint in regard to the body the
speech and the mind on the right mental
level and you realize okay so restrain
on the mind is not just denial of things
I just deny things to to not arise
because you well that's not even the
restraint on the level of the body the
restraint on the level of the body is
not acting out towards possibilities
that remain there in the world but you
choose to abstain from it and then your
abstaining your sense restraint exist
concurrently with those
possibilities neither are excluded you
just choose to maintain this in regard
to that that is still present very much
so
same with speech and then you recognize
oh so it's exactly the same principle
with the mind which is why as I said in
the sutas the whole thing is often
bundled together the same purification
it does not change or skip a beat and
become something else it's exactly the
same development all the way through but
yes that mental level needs to be
discerned of course so recognizing
images associated with sensuality images
associated with with ill will with any
hindrance and it's like okay so I don't
TR try to get rid of them I know that
they are there but I do not allow them
to become as I said the center of my
focus I to trying to get rid of them
fear them act out of them and so on and
that's the whole mindfulness of the body
that gets developed um because that's
what's always concurrently present with
regardless of what state of mind you're
in you have your body there enduring
simultaneously to that extent and that
doesn't change cannot change being being
fully aware of them is not awareness
it's absorption you can be fully
absorbed in them but then you're not
aware of yourself or anything else in
your experience or you can be like half
aware of something there but trying to
kind of ignore it and pretend it's not
there and like focus on the leaves and
everything else that you're doing and
equally you're not you're not actually
properly aware of the thing yeah you're
trying to ignore it
whereas because because these things can
really only operate where there's kind
of a degree of ignorance a degree of
like ignoring it ignoring one end of
your experience at the expense of the
other so I mean I'm just saying that
because like the concurrency and so on
can sound a bit abstract but really it's
more like it is it is is an intention
that's present being fully aware of it
not kind of fearing it not needing to
kind of get rid of it it it can't
continue to proliferate unless you
deliberately decide to do it and then is
that deliberation yeah boils down to the
very deliberation aspect of it so it's
it's just that obviously you need to you
need to First restrain other more
coarser forms of deliberation but once
you start to recognize that allowing
those images to take the center stage of
your experience it's an act it's a
deliberate act it's like oh I I need to
restrain that so yeah I agree like whether we
that so yeah I agree like whether we
talk about intention or concurrency or
all of these are kind of an indirect
ways of pointing at there is an act of
deliberation either towards I want to
get rid of these thoughts again it's a
deliberate kind of denial or I'll
deliberately give into them I'll just
they're pressuring me these images are
just just taking up all of my attention
span and there is always a point where
you choose to give into that and you
realize oh that's what you need to not
do so just don't give into that last
drop you can have all those images all
you want but if you don't allow that
last okay I I will allow them to take
the center stage you are in the clear
you in the clear and if you sustain that
last not giving in on that mental level
the establishment of virtue in virtue is
taking place and then exactly that comes down
place and then exactly that comes down
to that oh so yes you are actually
addressing things in the root so then
the future bodily Mis Behavior or verbal
misbehavior will be even less likely if
already on that mental level you are
you're recognizing that deliberate Act
of allowing these things giving in and
you're not doing it just that you let
them be but you don't do just that last
last drop and that's exactly what what
the sutas would be describing like he
doesn't welcome these thoughts so you
realize they're there it's not a
question of getting rid of them the
question is of not welcoming them so
when you have even thoughts of will will
that are unpleasant you do welcome them
to then try to resolve it or act out and
so on and there is that it feels that
it's almost like um
uh not subconscious but it kind of feels
like like an unconscious habit of you
just can't help but welcome first and
then try to resolve it and the reason
why you can't help but welcome first
mentally is cu physically you still have
not been thoroughly um developed in that
uprooting those wrong types of
deliberate acts nor verbally you have
not allowed those things to come up
closer to the mental level where whereby
the mental deliberation would become
more obvious and you do always see that as I
obvious and you do always see that as I
said like you can you can be dwelling
physically restrained but
then something that's not necessarily
UNH wholesome uh like and you kind of know
wholesome uh like and you kind of know
that in and of itself and nobody will be
upset but you know that it's rooted in
desire or you know that in you oh this
is rooted in ill will but it is not a
technical prohibition again saying
something but again you know that you
are doing it out of your
will so you deliberately then choose to
act out of that you deliberately choose
to to ignore the fact that yeah I know
it's technically nothing wrong but I'm
not here to deal with technicalities I'm
here to appro suffering and free myself
from craving and then you realize also
then there is no excuse there is no
exception if things are rooted in
obvious un wholesome states of mind I
should not say them doesn't matter what
happens to the
world so if you've been practicing that
long enough you will get to recognize
that even before it comes to like uh
Speech and pertaining to speech you
would recognize those types of same
deliberations and allowances and
welcoming and accepting and turning a
blind eye on that mental
level
and that's also it relates
to what you were saying about it um
being equivalent to the right getting
the right view because it also relates
to how the suas describe it as becoming
independent of others in the sense of um
not being able to put
any thing that others might say or no
matter how much the world sort of says
that this is okay no matter how many
other people who are all you know I
respect them and everything and they all
do it so it must be fine or whatever
other kind of notion or relying on
others to some extent it can't um kind
of get prioritized above what you know
your intention is going is rooted in
because you always know that you can't
um you can deny it you can cover it up
with other things but fundamentally if
you look it's always your intentions
will tell you what they are yeah and
that has to be that just has to be and
also then you could also see
how getting the right view is not an
accident it's not a like
a a lucky kind of experience that
somebody just stumbles upon know it's
just you go in this direction of
development and established in virtue
equals Right
View so yeah you realize then a person
could out of
Faith take on the
precepts learn about what's wholesome
what's UNH wholesome abstain from UNH
wholesome physically then when the M
when the mentally mind starts to
pressure them and they start you know
they might not be acting out physically
but they want to act out verbally or
distract them themselves verbally and
start engaging in all this then they
restrain that they recognize okay no I
will not give into that regardless of
whether it's acceptable or not I know
that it's rooted in the same type of
pressure that I'm restraining in regard
to bodily
Behavior so if they haven't been acting
out of speech then
either again it's like obviously depends
on the individual but he want want be
before long if this is done rightly you
would get to then see the same pressure
on the mental level so yes you're not
acting by the body you're not acting by
the speech but are you acting by the
mind are you acting out and as we
described acting out by the
mind incurs a certain that degree of losing
incurs a certain that degree of losing
self-awareness in regard to your own
thoughts choosing to deliberately allow
them to take the center stage not your
self-awareness in regard to the thoughts
the concurrency of it and so on but even
as I said without going into the
simultaneity and the principle behind
just as a mere practice you're okay so I
will not
deliberately allow my attention to rest
upon thoughts of sensuality when they
come up and start pressuring me
images I will not deliberately allow to
rest my attention myself my experience
as a whole on the images of ill will
they can be there
but I won't get that I won't like take
them and put them in front of me whereby
you know everything else is going to
start revolving around them so that's
how you don't act out of it in the same
sense when there is a a a possibility to
act out with your body in an UNH
wholesome manner you don't go and
destroy the tempting thing and kill
people that might excite you or or
irritate you or I'll have to get rid of
it that's how I free myself from the
will so you realize oh so you can't do
the same applies to the mind you can't
just oh I'll get rid of these thoughts
I'll forget about them I'll focus on
something else it's like well yeah but
again the same principle remains you
still the root of the problem is not
having those thoughts in the first place
the root is that you cannot not allow
them deliberately to take the Senter
stage so the training is there okay when
the thoughts are present I must have to
recognize that the liberate Act of
allowing them to to become sort of uh
established in this Center experience
and then everything I else everything
else I do becomes rooted in
it so abstaining from that last
allowance that last welcoming which is
as I said a deliberate act even if it
feels like automatic and subconscious
it's only because you haven't developed
your behavior sufficiently in those more
coarse
manners do you through your act or
through your reasoning are you putting
or implying the blame to be in those
images or in you wrongly attending to
them and that's the key here that is
really the yeah and you realize if
you're denying it if you're using uh
meditation concentration technique if
you're doing this in response to that
that implication is always going to be
there you think those images are the
problem and that's why you don't see the
root of the problem and that's why you
won't be free in regard to it and that's
why you won't be established in
virtue so it's you attending to them
wrongly in other words you letting them
take the Center Stage is the wrong
attention so abstaining from that
deliberate act you are purifying way of
attending to things
right that's it's not a separate
mystical practice oh I got to practice
Yono and then apply it no not allowing
them to take the center stage which is a
deliberate act however subtle it might
be is your yon Manara practice it's not
a question of focus really the question
is more of a a deliberate degree of
unfocus in in regard to things you
should be unfocused from yeah exactly
cuz the focus is you're being pressured
to focus exactly you're being pressured
to give in and welcome this and accept
it and then deal with it either through
denial or Indulgence doesn't matter but
first and foremost it's like that
pressure to take me and you is no that's
that's the root of also me taking it not
this thing being there or pressuring me
either and the breath is there
regardless of whether you attend to it
or not so that's well everything is
there regardless of whe you're attending
or not yeah the five Aggregates the body
the four postures the breath whichever
basis for your mindfulness you want to
take that's also why it equals like well
sort of safety sense of sense of safety
in terms of it being something that can
only ever be is totally in your hand
like nothing can no amount of images y
that come up if if your uh view to some
degree implies that the problem in those
is in those images you can never feel
safe because it's always possible that
some image can you absolutely there's no
way to hide from them no matter what you
can do it can still it still might be
possible that this might arise and
there's no way of knowing or being sure
that this can never arise again exactly
but so like to the extent that you have
some kind of notion or fear or wait what
if this comes up or what if that comes
up you can sort of know that
your um your virtue is not completely
establish L because if it were virtue
that is uh being established in virtue
means recognizing virtue as something
that no nothing can come in between
between you and it it it is it is it is
always in your hand yeah yeah it's just
as I said for most people it's too
subtle because they haven't been
practicing sensory straint properly with
the body nor with the speech so this
feels like too subtle to notice and thus
when you say you should not welcome
these thoughts for people that equals
must get rid of those thoughts but
that's not the same statement but if you
if you look at your intentions on the
level of body and the speech and as I
said not act out of them and then endure
the mental pressure and states in regard
to it this deliberate Act of accepting
images on that subtle level will become
apparent somebody said something
upsetting there is a pressure there is
an influx of images that are associated
with that person in a like a manner of
ill will while I'm sitting here talking to
will while I'm sitting here talking to
you I could choose now to withdraw my
attention from sitting and talking to
you and allow these thoughts to take the
center stage and start to revolve and
feed and this and that and I should have
said I will say next time or I was like
no I'll let that domain that entire
domain of the mind that revolves around
these images I'll let it be there but I
will not allow it to deliberately take
over me that's it that's it just that
last drop and you oh it's a it's a
restraint it's exact same principle of
restraining the body restraining the
speech I'm restraining the Mind
restraining the Mind means not allowing
your mind to take over you whereby you
lose your selfawareness does not mean
denying my mind denying these thoughts
trying to get rid of them trying to
counter them or something because you
don't do that in regard to things that
tempt you by the body you're not
countering them constantly you know if
you see something beautiful you go and
destroy it and make it ugly no so
restraining your mind means restraining
basically the images when they present
themselves from overwhelming you in a
sense of making you lose self-awareness
and making you basically allow them
accept them as the center stage of your
efforts and
acts and that's why that whole kind of
the necessity of purifying your bodily
Behavior first it's not
optional like if you're still giving in
by the
body all these things will remain
abstract it will be too subtle to see CU
even the bodily intention of its C
nature nature you still give in which
means you still imply basically that the
problem is in things that tempted you
that's why you give into them or you act
out of them with anger or whichever
way so that needs to be contained
first and then on the subtler level
speech same things you say things you
want to say pressure to say and so
on same recognition is it rooted in the
pressure I won't say it I'll say
everything else if I have to but I won't
say that I will not deliberately accept
it like but what if it stays there for
like 6 months pressuring me doesn't
matter if it stays for 60 months 60
years six
earons I I won't say it I won't accept
that to be to I won't accept that act I
won't accept those images and that's
usually why people give in what if this
lasts forever it's like well that's the
training pressuring images they want you to
pressuring images they want you to
accept
them so if you don't accept them they're
going to obviously pressure you more to
accept them but they can't do anything
else to you except trying to pressure
you into accepting them so as you might
feel like scary and overwhelming
initially but you well that is the root
to the problem everything else that
follows all this all the things that I
previously restrained all the UNH
wholesome was all just the result of
this accepting images of the UN
wholesome nature deliberately allowing
them to take the center
stage so if I never do that I don't have
to worry about anything else at all even
if those images keep even if they keep
coming as I said for next 60 years you
realize well not accepting them it's
kind of effortless I don't need to go
anywhere climb the
mountains I I don't need to do anything
except mentally not not accept them
deliberately and allow them to take the
Senter state that's all I need to do so
it is peaceful it's not a fight it's not
a it's exactly yeah a task and you
realize why it would result in equinity
completely like there will be no room
for ill will nor any room for
sensuality I was going to say like you
realize that kind of fearing what if
this pressure keeps pressuring me for
whatever me that's actually
that's the that's why it's pressuring
it's not it's not it's not it that it's
pressuring you if you kind of stop
fearing it pressuring you and you just
say well yeah you can keep for however
long it takes infinite infinitely like
infinite infinitely patient I suppose in
regard to it it it cannot there's no
room for any pressure there because if
you're infinitely patient there's that's
almost like the definition of just
something that's not bothering you at
all that's the point developing patience
in regard to the right things people can
develop patience in regard to things
that do not necess that still imply the
wrong view they still imply that the
problem is in the wrong place but when
it comes to this true restraint true
physical restraint verbal restraint once
you recognize the deliberate acceptance
of unh wholesome thoughts on the mental
level okay so if I develop patience in
regard to that then yeah that's Prett
much the root of the development
and that is like the the true kind of
patient endurance obviously patient
endurance has to be exercised in regard
to the body when you're pressured to act
in regard to the verbal when you're
pressured to act but the root of it is
patient endurance in regard to the
images associated with un wholesome they
want me to accept them they want me to
deliberately allow them welcome them to
take the center stage then even if I
then practice mindfulness and read the
sutas and do all of this all all of that
I do in response all of that I do as a
way of managing the fact that I couldn't
help but welcome them and open the door
for them so not welcoming them does not
equal denying them it simply equals not
welcoming them even if they remain
sitting in your face for as long as they
want oh that's the
practice learning how to sustain that
Yara the right way of attending to them
as if you are not welcome regardless of
everything else and then they'll stop coming
completely and you realize yeah you
truly obliterated
them destroyed them surpass
them like they're not coming up anymore
factually you say they're gone you say
this is the uh the the definition the
difference between it's a mind or the definition in
between it's a mind or the definition in
the sutas that you read about quite
often limited and unlimited you so your
mind is limited by this ill will and now
it is not limited by that thing it's not
bound to it and well yes yes there would
be there would be like a a different
degrees of limit as well like see once
this the once this becomes more and more
apparent through being rightly
restrained rightly established in your
precept in your speech then you start to
recognize that the the deliberate
welcoming of thoughts obviously you know
in not as I said it's not going to be
perfect overnight so you might you might
not do it but then you might do a little
bit so to the extent that you allow it
to take the center stage to the center
you you welcome it to that extent that
you're limited by so you might be less
limited that before but if there is the
slightest ex extent of welcoming such
thoughts to that extent there is a limit
so when you truly then mind is
completely free from slightest degree of
welcoming those thoughts you mind is
unlimited and that's basically when
you're uh surmounted the five
hindrances okay the ill will is not
limiting you you deliberately allowing
it to Center St take the center stage is
is the limit that's the what limits it
that's what narrows it down yeah